<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-09-05T16:16:20-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Michael Ge | Digital Artist | Developer</title><entry><title type="html">geemichael 2.0</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/technology/2017/09/05/geemichael-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="geemichael 2.0" /><published>2017-09-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/technology/2017/09/05/geemichael-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/technology/2017/09/05/geemichael-2/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.geemichael.com&quot;&gt;geemichael.com&lt;/a&gt; is here, and it’s beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, sort of. It looks no different, but it’s a lot better than it was before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, I took it upon myself to open the godforsaken codebase of this website to make some updates. I quickly found myself knee-deep in spaghetti code, copy-pasting line after atrocious line of ugly, ID-specific HTML text, finding hacky solutions to buggy CSS I never had time to fix, and sending it all away to some unlucky Bluehost server to parse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was while trying to fix a rogue right-floating image that I decided &lt;b&gt;enough is enough&lt;/b&gt;. Time for a website rewrite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;header&quot;&gt;Why Bluehost Wasn't Right for Me&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, I was shelling out a comparatively hefty chunk of my wallet to Bluehost for its web-hosting service. Don’t get me wrong, Bluehost is great for businesses and services requiring a server-side backend. Unfortunately, there were a couple of things that bothered me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;invite&quot;&gt;PHP Backend&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bluehost is old. Like, 2003 old. It got early traction, exploded from there, and since then has injected tons of bells and whistles into their product, making it more robust and efficient for both naive and veteran users. It’s safe to say that Bluehost now provides a behemoth of a service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, all of that went to their backend language PHP, and they never added support for other server-side languages. I’m a big fan of Node and am now dabbling more and more in Flask. My lightweight Arch Linux machine makes development in Javascript and Python easy compared to the hulking Visual Studio software Windows users lug around. While PHP is certainly a feasible option to develop in, building this website was in and of itself a project in learning web development, and I didn’t find learning an outdated technology particularly interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;invite&quot;&gt;Static Websites&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, I wasn’t even using most of the technology Bluehost had to offer for &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.geemichael.com&quot;&gt;geemichael.com&lt;a&gt;. My site is a portfolio for showcasing my artwork and code projects, not an interactive form-submission and data-processing system. The service was simply too hefty for my needs. Having something lightweight and easy to manage locally was a must for me.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;invite&quot;&gt;Money&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, it’s not free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;header&quot;&gt;Jekyll and Github Pages&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of a push to encourage student engagement in computer science, Github offers one free static web-hosting server for each Github account. The site offers “unlimited” storage (within reason per Github’s &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/what-is-my-disk-quota/&quot;&gt;repository rules&lt;/a&gt;). Github Pages is also closely integrated with &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, a static-site HTML generator running on the templating engine &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/Shopify/liquid/wiki&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;. This was especially interesting to me because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiar git workflow with version control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Templating: goodbye copy-pasting, hello YAML files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's free!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what a good change it was. Suddenly, masses of art-panel divs were reduced to a single for loop, naming conventions for titles and footers are now uniform throughout the codebase, and any time I need to add or remove data information, I can edit a much easier to read set of YAML files. The version control is a major plus to my workflow, and Github sends me an email if there is ever an error during Jekyll compilation. The biggest bonus of switching to Jekyll, however, was that I now have the tools to start something I’ve always wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;header&quot;&gt;The Blog&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll’s main use is for writing blogs easily and quickly. Simply by designating a template, I can write a blog post in a markdown file (or have it generated by some richtext formatter), compile it in Jekyll, and have everything easily published onto my website in a few minutes. This has quickly become the most exciting aspect of my website rewrite. Now, I’m not only maintaining a shrine of self-glorification, but I’ve also built up the infrastructure to allow me to share my thoughts with the world. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;header&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, welcome to the new &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;http://geemichael.com&quot;&gt;geemichael.com&lt;/a&gt;. While it’s still pretty chunky-looking, I’ll be having a much happier time touching up the design aspects in between breaks during the semester. The process of moving over was relatively painless; Jekyll is an easy-to-learn tool, and my domain name was purchased under NameCheap, so there weren’t issues with halting my Bluehost subscription. Better yet, I came out of this with a whole blog section, allowing me to document all these wonderful things I’ve learned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My CSS is still pretty ugly though, but I think that would be true regardless of how I wrote my website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="liquid" /><category term="static site generator" /><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">geemichael.com is here, and it’s beautiful.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">C4D: Unreliable Booles</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/graphics/2017/09/05/boole-unreliability/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="C4D: Unreliable Booles" /><published>2017-09-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/graphics/2017/09/05/boole-unreliability</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/graphics/2017/09/05/boole-unreliability/">&lt;p&gt;I came across an interesting issue while trying to displace the surface of an otherwise static object. When using the Boolean tool to intersect two objects with an animated displacement deformer, the point of intersection occasionally fails to render on certain frames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a sample of the desired image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/swishswishfish.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original goal was to animate the upper surface of the water cube with a displacement deformer while maintaining proper contact with the sand on the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do so, I created a larger, invisible cube with the displacement deformer and intersected it with my water cube. To animate the water, I used the animation settings on the displacement cube’s noise shader to affect the water cube’s surface when boolean joined. The result was the shimmering water surface we see in the image, at least for certain frames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I tried rendering out more frames, I soon found that the top geometry of the water cube would occasionally &lt;i&gt;disappear&lt;/i&gt;. This is especially odd since I didn’t set any keyframes regarding the visibility of the mesh. After a couple hours of playing around, I’ve come to the conclusion that, depending on how the animation displaces the top surface, certain displacements would cause the top to disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t figure out why this would be the case. According to &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Cinema4D/comments/4djnmo/c4d_boole_a_intersect_b_object_disappearing_when/&quot;&gt;this reddit post&lt;/a&gt;, there might be a bug relating to the instability of booles in C4D. The best alternative (and probably best solution from the get-go) I can think of would be to use a finite bounding box. I’ll have to try constraining a deformer and applying the displacement over the upper region without this boolean method. The initial concern is that the geometry vertically along the walls is a single polygon, so the deformation would cause breaking holes in the mesh, but perhaps it’ll work fine after subdividing the walls…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="cinema 4d r15" /><category term="boole" /><category term="displacement deformer" /><category term="animation" /><summary type="html">I came across an interesting issue while trying to displace the surface of an otherwise static object. When using the Boolean tool to intersect two objects with an animated displacement deformer, the point of intersection occasionally fails to render on certain frames.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my Tech Blog!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/technology/2017/08/30/tech-intro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my Tech Blog!" /><published>2017-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/technology/2017/08/30/tech-intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/technology/2017/08/30/tech-intro/">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my tech blog! Here, you’ll find posts about the various things I’m working on as well as tips and insights I’ve gained during the project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="intro" /><summary type="html">Welcome to my tech blog! Here, you’ll find posts about the various things I’m working on as well as tips and insights I’ve gained during the project.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my Problem Solving Blog!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/problems/2017/08/30/problems-intro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my Problem Solving Blog!" /><published>2017-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/problems/2017/08/30/problems-intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/problems/2017/08/30/problems-intro/">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my problem solving blog! Here, you’ll find posts about interesting problems and riddles I’ve encountered as well as how I solved them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="intro" /><summary type="html">Welcome to my problem solving blog! Here, you’ll find posts about interesting problems and riddles I’ve encountered as well as how I solved them.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my Graphic Art Blog!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/graphics/2017/08/30/graphic-art-intro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my Graphic Art Blog!" /><published>2017-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/graphics/2017/08/30/graphic-art-intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/graphics/2017/08/30/graphic-art-intro/">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my graphic art blog! Here, you’ll find posts about techniques I’ve discovered while creating and designing graphic art.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="intro" /><summary type="html">Welcome to my graphic art blog! Here, you’ll find posts about techniques I’ve discovered while creating and designing graphic art.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my Data Science Blog!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/datasci/2017/08/30/datasci-intro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my Data Science Blog!" /><published>2017-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/datasci/2017/08/30/datasci-intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/datasci/2017/08/30/datasci-intro/">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my data science blog! Here, you’ll find posts about the various things I’m working on as well as tips and insights I’ve gained during the project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="intro" /><summary type="html">Welcome to my data science blog! Here, you’ll find posts about the various things I’m working on as well as tips and insights I’ve gained during the project.</summary></entry></feed>